[\fs30}火線狙擊
- Oh, my God! - Frank, thank God! I'm dead.
- 噢 我的天 - 弗蘭克 謝天謝地 完了
I'm dead.
這下我死定了
Frank, I'm sorry. I got lost. This town is so confusing.
弗蘭克 對不起 我迷路了 這裡像個迷魂陣
What a day. My wife had to work early.
今天這鬼日子 我妻子一早上班去了
My kid was crying when I took him to new school. He hated to leave Chicago.
所以 我送孩子去新學校的路上 他哭個不停 他不想離開芝加哥
- It broke my heart, Frank. - Any more excuses?
- 我的心都碎了 弗蘭克 - 還有別的藉口嗎？
- No. - Good. In the future be punctual.
- 沒有了 - 那就好 和我一起工作就得準時
- You got it? - I'm sorry. It won't happen again.
- 明白了？- 對不起 弗蘭克 以後不會了
- Frank, how are you doing? - It's good to see you again.
- 你好 弗蘭克 - 見到你很高興
- Hi, Marty. Sorry we're late. - Al, go help Jimmy and Raul.
- 嘿 馬蒂 抱歉我們遲到了 - 艾爾 能否到下面幫吉米和波爾？
Yeah, sure. This is his.
好 當然 這是他的
- You don't trust me? - I live in a crappy neighborhood.
- 你信不過我 - 我生活在一個不好的環境
- Have you got that funny money? - Yeah. Right here.
- 鈔票弄到了？- 是的 就在這兒
It looks good. It looks real good.
看上去不錯 相當好
- We're in business. - Excellent.
- 我們可以做生意了 - 當然
There's just one problem. This guy Al...
但有一個問題 弗蘭克 這個傢伙 艾爾
He keeps asking all these questions about my counterfeiter.
他不停地問我製造偽鈔的問題
- Really? - He asked too many questions.
- 是嗎？- 對 他問得太多了
My instinct usually tells me when something's wrong.
我的直覺一向很准
And there's something wrong. So I had him followed.
現在它告訴我這裡有問題 所以我派人跟蹤他
He's a Secret Service agent, Frank.
他是該死的特工部警探 弗蘭克
- What do you think I ought to do? - Be sure the body doesn't wash up.
- 你說我該怎麼辦 弗蘭克？- 扔進河裡別讓屍體被水沖到岸上
I want you to pop him for me, okay?
你替我幹掉他好嗎？
- I think maybe you're with him. - You came to me, remember?
- 我想你也許和他是一夥的 - 是你來找我的 記得嗎？
- So pop him. Show me I'm an asshole. - I'm just a businessman.
- 那就幹掉他 證明我是小人 - 我只是個生意人
So pop him...
那就幹掉他
and let's do some business.
咱們好談生意
Yes, Frank, that's what I'm looking for.
做得好 弗蘭克 我要的就是這個
Come on, let's go get an omelet.
走吧 咱們去吃煎蛋
I know a good place.
我知道一個好地方
Let me get my pistol.
把我的槍還給我
My gun?
我的槍？
You're under arrest.
你被捕了
You're under arrest, too. Secret Service.
你也被捕了 我也是特工部警探
You knew from the weight of the gun that it was empty, right?
你知道那槍是空的 對嗎？我是說從重量上可以判斷槍裡沒子彈
There could have been one bullet there.
有可能裡面剩一顆子彈
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
Hey, Frank.
嘿 弗蘭克
Do you think we can go someplace and talk about this?
嗯 弗蘭克 咱們找個地方談談這事好嗎？
You killed guys before, Frank?
你以前殺過人嗎 弗蘭克？
Does it get to you?
會覺得不安嗎？
It gets to you.
你覺得不安了
I don't like this undercover stuff. I was so scared.
我可能不適合幹這種臥底工作 當時我嚇壞了
I joined the Secret Service...
你知道 我加入特工部是因為
to protect people.
我一向喜歡保護別人
You like the idea of throwing yourself in front of a gun?
將自己置於槍口之下
Hoping you get hit instead of the guy you're protecting?
希望子彈射中自己 而不是你保護的人
I don't know. Maybe I'm....
不知道 也許我
- Maybe I'm just wrong for the job. - You're a good man, Al.
- 也許我不是幹這行的料 - 你是個好人 艾爾
- You'll make a good agent. - How do you know?
- 會成為一名好特工 - 你怎麼知道？
I know things about people.
我很會看人
- Come on, let's eat. - I've got to go home to my family.
- 走吧 咱們去吃點東西 - 我想回家 擁抱老婆孩子
A lot of guys warned me you were a pain in the ass.
我剛來時很多人警告我 說你是個討厭的傢伙
They were right.
他們說得對
- I'll see you in the office. - Damn! The office.
- 咱們辦公室見 - 噢 糟了 辦公室
- Monroe wants us to check this out. - I'll take care of it.
- 蒙羅要我們去調查一個瘋子 - 我去處理好了
- Ill go with you. - No. Go hug your wife and kid.
- 我跟你去 - 不用 你回家去擁抱老婆孩子
約瑟夫麥克勞利
歡樂大道3155號
找經理
I am not a noisy lady.
我不是愛管閒事的人
I do not snoop, but the smoke alarm was going off.
我從不亂打聽 可火警響了
I got scared.
我嚇壞了
I got more scared when I saw what was inside.
見到屋裡的東西後就更害怕了
The smoke was from crumbs in the oven he left on.
火警是烤爐裡的麵包渣引起的
Thirty-one years I've been in this country.
在這個國家住了31年
I love the United States. I've been to the White House.
我喜歡美國 我參觀過白宮
Only in the United States can just anybody go to visit the President.
只有美國允許任何人參觀總統的家
So when I saw this, these killing things...
所以看到這些暗殺的照片後
I called the police. They called the Secret Service.
我打電話報警 他們說要報告特工部
新時代汽車模型
But two days, you do not come.
但是兩天了你都沒來
The President gets 1,400 threats a year. We've got to check them all.
總統每年大約受到1400個恐嚇 我們全都得調查
他們可以送我進毒氣室
但我出名了
甘迺迪一生的追求
我一天就能得到
- You say his name's McCauley? - No, McCrawley, from Denver.
- 你說這傢伙叫麥克勞利？- 約瑟夫默庫勞利 從科羅拉多 丹佛來
I remember it like yesterday. I cried and cried.
我還記得就像昨天 我哭得很傷心
- Joseph McCrawley, Denver, right? - That is right.
- 丹佛的約瑟夫麥克勞利 對嗎？- 對的
Died over 30 years ago, age 11.
30年前就死了 年僅11歲
Your guy got a duplicate birth certificate...
那個人一定是用假出生證
then used it to get a driver's license.
辦的駕照
- Thanks, Jack. - See you.
- 謝謝 傑克 - 再見
Federal Agents. Open up!
聯邦特工 快開門
Oh, my God! That's you.
噢 天啊 那是你
- Yeah? - Frank Horrigan?
- 喂？- 弗蘭克霍利根？
- Yeah? - The Secret Service agent?
- 是 - 特工部警探？
- Yeah. What did I win? - My God, it's really you?
- 是 我中了什麼獎？- 我的天 真的是你？
- Who the hell is this? - That was you in my apartment.
- 你是什麼人？- 是你昨晚進了我的公寓
- McCrawley? - Why not call me Booth?
- 麥克勞利？- 還是叫我布思
- Why not Oswald? - Booth had flair and panache.
- 或者叫奧斯華？- 布思刺殺了林肯
The leap to the stage after he shot Lincoln.
之後一躍成名 有了炫耀的本錢
- Where are you? - Closer than you'd imagine.
- 你在哪兒？- 比你想像的要近
It's very exciting to talk to you. I feel like I know you.
很高興能與你交談 我覺得好像很瞭解你
How is that?
哦 怎麼會？
I've read about you and seen photos. You were JFK'S favorite agent.
我讀過有關你的報導 看過照片 你曾是甘迺迪最喜歡的特工
But that was a long time ago. What keeps you going?
不過那是很久以前的事了 這麼多年你怎麼還沒改行？
What about we get together and have a drink, we can talk about that.
要不找個地方見面喝一杯？咱們可以好好談談
I think the less you know about me, the better.
我很樂意 不過我想最好還是保持點距離
Why?
為什麼？
- Because I'm planning to kill the President. - You shouldn't have said that.
- 因為我打算刺殺總統 - 你不該亂講這種話
Threatening the President is a federal offense, even if you don't mean it.
威脅總統是刑事罪行 哪怕你並不是認真的
I mean it.
我是認真的
One need only be willing to trade one's own life for the President's.
甘迺迪說過刺客需要的只是願意用自己的一生換總統一命 對嗎？
- That's right. - I'm willing.
- 是這樣 - 我願意
Going up against you raises the game to a much higher level.
而且能和你對抗 這遊戲又升了一個層次
Fate has brought us together, Frank.
命運將我們聯在一起
- I just can't get over the irony. - What irony?
- 我不能放過這麼有諷刺意義的事 - 什麼諷刺意義？
Your intimate involvement with the assassinations of two presidents.
兩次總統被暗殺你都親眼目睹
Hang on a second. I've got something on the stove.
等一下 我爐子上煮著東西
He was a tenant for three weeks.
他在那樓裡只住了3個星期
What's really weird is the other tenants never really saw him.
最奇怪的是其他房客也見過他卻沒人看清過他的面目
Statements vary. He was between 58 and 62.
每個人的形容都不同 他身高約在5英尺8到6英尺2之間
Between 165 and 180 pounds.
體重大約165磅到180磅
- Age? - Between 28 and 45.
- 年齡？- 28至45歲
Before an election, panic is what you've got on a good day.
離大選還有兩個月 每天都會有恐慌
- They're waiting for you. - Hey, Frank.
- 他們在等你 - 嘿 弗蘭克
- Sam. - It's been a long time.
- 山姆 - 好久沒有在這兒見到你了
- I hear the new director isn't much fun. - I've been the director for two years.
- 對 聽說新局長很厲害 - 我當局長快兩年了
Al D'Andrea. You know Matt Wilder.
艾爾丹德利 弗蘭克 認識麥特王爾德嗎？
He still owes me $20 from Super Bowl 21.
超級杯球賽打賭他還欠我20塊錢呢
This is agent-in-charge Bill Watts and Lilly Raines.
負責保衛的特工比爾沃茨  還有莉莉雷恩斯
- She's very pretty for a secretary. - And you're very old for an agent.
- 這裡的秘書越來越漂亮 - 一線特工越來越老
Lilly's an agent.
莉莉也是特工 弗蘭克
I know that, I just wanted to see if she had a sense of humor.
這我知道 只是想看看她有沒有幽默感
Have a seat. Let's talk about this guy.
都坐吧 我們談談這個傢伙
I guess we're calling him Booth for now.
我們暫且稱他為 布思 好了
Yeah.
是
- What do you know about him? - He's dangerous.
- 你對他瞭解多少 弗蘭克？- 他很危險
- How do you know? - I know things about people.
- 你怎麼知道？- 我很會看人 莉莉
Why didn't you take steps to know more that first night?
請問 第一天晚上你為什麼沒採取正確步驟馬上調查他？
- We had a busy day. - Too busy to investigate properly?
- 那天我們很忙 比爾 - 忙得沒空深入調查？
- Your report says you only in the room 10 min. - I didn't have a warrant.
- 你的報告上說你在他房間裡待了10分鐘 - 我沒有搜查令
- Given your reputation... - What reputation are you talk about?
- 根據你作秘密工作的名聲 - 你指的是什麼名聲 比爾？
- All right, let's get back on track. - I'd like to know what reputation is referring to?
- 好了 還是說正題吧 - 我想知道他指的是什麼名聲
Let us drop it.
還是別說了
Am I paranoid, or is he busting my balls?
是我有精神病 還是他故意惹我？
Probably a little of both.
可能兩者都有一點
Bill, there was a time around here when I was almost as arrogant as you.
知道嗎 比爾 想當年我在這兒和你現在一樣狂妄
I don't have time for this. I've got to pull 75 agents out of Miami.
我沒時間討論這個 我要從邁阿密調來75名特工
Keep me posted, Sam, will you?
有事隨時通知我 山姆
- So what do we do with this guy? - We keep investigating.
- 打算怎麼對付這傢伙？- 我們將繼續調查
- Meanwhile, if you could, have my phone tapped. - What make he call again?
- 同時 如果可以的話 監聽我的電話 - 你怎麼知道他還會打來？
- He'll call again. He's got panache. - Panache?
- 他會再打 他想炫耀 - 炫耀？
- Yes, it means flamboyance. - I know what it means.
- 對 意思是引人注意 - 嗯 我知道是什麼意思
- Really? I had to look it up. - All right, we'll tap your phone.
- 是嗎？我得查字典 - 好吧 我們監聽你的電話
By the way, Watts isn't nearly as arrogant as you were.
順便說一句 弗蘭克 甘迺迪重用你的那些年 你比沃茨狂妄一百倍
Just what reputation was Watts referring to, Sam?
瓦特剛才說我的名聲什麼意思 山姆
You know.
你心裡很清楚
Is it because I'm considered a borderline burn-out...
是因為大家認為我老不中用
with questionable social skills?
而且人緣極差？
What do you want to talk to me about, besides your reputation?
除了你的名聲 還有什麼事想跟我討論？
I want to be assigned to the President.
我想擔任總統衛士
- Protection? After all these years? Frank, you're a dinosaur. - That is right.
- 保護總統？這麼多年之後？弗蘭克 你已經成了恐龍 - 是的
- This guy's gonna make a try, I get to be there. - Watts will fight me.
- 這傢伙會來真的 我必須在現場 - 沃茨會跟我打翻天
Then fight him back.
那你就還手
You owe it to me after 30 years doing your favours.
30年來你欠我不少人情
- If you knew how many times I protect your job? - I get to come back.
- 知道我多少次替你保住飯碗嗎？- 我必須回來 山姆
Do you really want to stand post again? At your age?
你真的想在一線站崗 弗蘭克？這把年紀？
Yeah, I've got at least one pair of good shoes somewhere.
對 在我衣櫃某個角落至少還能找到一雙體面的鞋
We're stopping. Traveler wants to work the ropes.
各崗位注意 我是沃茨 現在停車 旅客要到場外
The French President's coming. Get a security man up here.
法國總統要陪他下車 派個警衛過來
All right, let us go.
好了 走吧
Damn it!
見鬼
- What's going on here? - Horrigan had a heart attack.
- 出了什麼事？- 霍利根心臟病突發
- Hey, are you okay? - Get the hell out of here.
- 嘿 老兄 你怎麼樣？- 快滾開
- What's going on? - I had a call about a cardiac case.
- 出了什麼事？- 我接到電話說有人心臟病發
- Are you all right, Frank? - I'm on my break here.
- 沒事吧 弗蘭克？- 我只是在這兒休息一下
I get it, you bastards.
明白了 這些壞蛋
Who's the wise guy?
那聰明傢伙是誰？
Okay, everybody, back to work.
好了 都回去工作吧
- All right, who was the joker? Who call these guys? - It may not have been a joke.
- 誰開的玩笑？誰打的電話？- 有可能不是玩笑
- You were looking peaked today. - I'll find out who he is and pay him back in spades.
- 今天你看上去筋疲力盡 - 讓我查出誰搞的鬼 絕饒不了這小子
How can you be sure it was a him?
你怎麼知道是 小子？
- You've missed my street, Al. - Why don't you have a car?
- 嘿 你錯過我下車的地方 艾爾 - 弗蘭克 你幹嘛不買輛車？
I lived in New York a long time. I like public transportation.
在紐約住了很多年 我喜歡公共汽車
If you like buses, that is great, why make me go out of my way?
你喜歡公共汽車？很好 弗蘭克 那為什麼每天讓我繞遠？
I like your company.
我喜歡跟你作伴
- He's a weird-looking guy. - Yeah, if he still looks like that.
- 他的樣子很怪 對嗎？- 對 如果他現在還長這樣的話
Pull up over here, will you?
在前面停一下 好嗎？
The President's election troubles were hardly apparent today.
總統的政治麻煩 今天中午並沒有顯露出來
He and the French President stopped twice to greet the crowds.
他和法國總統的車隊曾兩次停下 問候熱情的人群
The Senate has yet to react to the new French trade agreement.
還不知道參議院是否會歡迎兩位領導人新簽署的貿易協定
Meanwhile, the French will host a formal dinner at their embassy for the President.
同時 法國大使將在大使館舉辦正式晚宴答謝美國總統
Presidential advisors are pleased...
據說總統的政治顧問非常滿意
with the publicity this has brought in an election year.
法國方面在大選之年公開感謝總統
It's a weird sub-culture, Al. I'd like you send some agents to check this things.
一個古怪的亞文化群 艾爾 你派一些人去
- Ask about some wackos. - I'll get on in the morning.
- 查看有沒有瘋子之類的人 - 明天一早就辦
Hang on, I've got the other line.
等一下 有電話打進來
- Yeah? - Frank.
- 喂 - 弗蘭克
- Booth, how are you doing? - I'm fine, thanks.
- 布思？你好嗎？- 我很好 謝謝
Hang on just a second, I'll get rid of the other call.
請等一下 讓我掛斷另一個電話
- You got it? - We get it, keep on the line.
- 聽到了嗎？- 聽到了 弗蘭克 繼續跟他說話直到我們追蹤到號碼
- Yeah? - Trying to trace me?
- 好了 - 想追蹤我的電話 弗蘭克？
- Why didn't I think of that? - You do, or you're not the adversary I hoped for.
- 我怎麼事先沒想到？- 你想到了 否則就不是我期待的對手
- How are you? I was worried about you today. - Why?
- 你還好嗎？今天我真為你擔心 - 為什麼？
In the motorcade, I thought you were going to pass out.
車隊行進時 我以為你就要昏倒了
You really should get in shape for that kind of duty.
你真的該為這種工作鍛煉身體
- Yeah, maybe you're right. - By the way, I'm watching your movie.
- 也許你說的對 - 告訴你 我正在看你的電影
- Movie? - November 1963. Kennedy's last days.
- 電影？- 1963年11月甘迺迪的最後一天
The arrival in Texas.
他抵達德克薩斯
It must have been exciting for you.
你一定很興奮 弗蘭克
Dallas. That morning at Love Field.
達拉斯？那天早上在拉夫菲爾德機場
You all look so radiant. JFK, Jackie and you.
你看上去容光煥發 甘迺迪 凱薩琳 還有你
You look so young and able, Frank.
你的樣子年輕有為 弗蘭克
What did happen to you that day?
那天你究竟是怎麼回事？
Only one agent react to the gun fire, and you were closer than he was.
槍響後 只有一個特工有反應 可你離總統比他近
You must have looked up at that window, but you didn't react.
你抬頭看德克薩斯圖書倉庫的窗戶 可你沒有馬上行動
Late at night when the demons come..
每當後半夜魔鬼再現
do you see the rifle coming out of the window, or Kennedy's head being blown apart?
你是否看見步槍伸出視窗？或是否看到甘迺迪的頭被打碎？
If you'd reacted to the first shot, could you get there in time to stop the big bollet?
如果第一聲槍響後你立即行動 能及時趕到擋住第二顆子彈嗎？
If you had, that could've been your head being blown apart.
若真如此 被打碎的可能是你的腦袋
Do you wish you'd succeeded, or is life too precious?
你希望能成功嗎 弗蘭克？還是生命太寶貴？
What's done is done.
過去的事過去了
I have that Esquire article on the tenth anniversary...
在甘迺迪遇刺10周年時 紳士 雜誌發表過一篇文章
about you and the other agents.
報導了你和所有那天 在場的其他特工的情況
So sad how your wife left you and took your little daughter.
真悲慘 你的妻子離你而去 並帶走了你的小女兒
You were so forthright about your drinking problem.
你很坦率地承認你成了酒鬼
And that you weren't easy to live with.
並且很難和人相處
I was so moved by your honesty.
你的誠實讓我好感動
The world can be a cruel place to an honest man.
這個世界對一個誠實的人來說是殘酷的
What about you, Booth? What's your story?
那你呢 布思？你有什麼經歷呢？
It's an epic saga.
我的事蹟是個偉大傳奇
I'll talk to you again soon. It's nice to have a friend.
咱們下次再聊 有個朋友真好
- Did you get him? - We got him.
- 查到了沒有？- 查到了
He could have a device that makes it look like he's using another number.
他可能有種裝置 能擾亂號碼追蹤器偽造電話識別信號
- This device, how could he get it? - He could build one.
- 他可能在什麼地方弄到這個裝置 - 他能自己造一個
- You can not trace the call? - We could run a parity check.
- 那你追查不出他的電話？- 可以用同位
- You can trace the call? - Not if it's a para-analog line.
- 你是說能夠追查到？- 要是他用老式雙股類比線路就不行
Damn it, would you give a straight answer, or I have my partner shoot off his foot.
該死 傑克 你能不能直接回答？否則我讓我的搭檔把他的腳打斷
OK, OK, he calls again, you keep him on the line. We'll see what we can do.
好吧 好吧 他還會打來 你要儘量拖住他 我們會盡一切努力
Right?
對嗎 托尼？
You might suggest that the police don't knock down any more doors.
你最好提醒警方 不要再破門而入了
I have that Esquire article about you and the other agents.
紳士 雜誌報導了你和所有那天在場的其他特工的情況
So sad how your wife left you and took your little daughter.
真悲慘 你的妻子離你而去 並帶走了你的小女兒
You were so forthright about your drinking problem.
你很坦率地承認你成了酒鬼
And that you weren't easy to live with.
並且很難和人相處
I was so moved by your honesty.
你的誠實讓我好感動
- Why play it for me? - We'd like you to cancel the President's dinner tomrrow night.
- 幹嘛放給我聽？- 我們要你取消總統明晚的宴會
The dinner at the French Embassy?
你是說國宴？在法國使館？
This close to the election?
知道在大選臨近時安排這些活動花了我多長時間嗎？
He manipulated the phone system.
這傢伙能干擾電話系統
He could have knowledge of explosives, that would be problems.
如果他懂得炸藥 可能會出問題
- Do your job. There'll be no problems. - It's not hard to have weapons inside the embassy.
- 你們幹好自己的事 就不會有任何問題 - 帶武器進入使館並不困難
You think the French want to knock off the President?
你認為法國人想打死總統？
Why does every chief of staff...
為什麼每個白宮總官都認為
You have no reason to belive that this is anything but an idle threat.
你沒有理由相信這個傢伙 比其他幾千個恐嚇者更危險
You want me to cancel a state dinner and risk offending the French?
可你要我更改世界上最有權力的人的行程 冒犯4千萬法國人
This guy's pushed your buttons and you're overreacting a little.
是不是這傢伙觸動了你的痛處 讓你有點反應過度？
- I'm trying to protect your boss. - So am I.
- 我只是想保護你的老闆 該死的 - 我也一樣
We're trailing 12 points in the polls, and the election's in six weeks.
民意調查我們落後12個百分點 他若不出席6個星期後就會失業
- He's got to be seen. - Even if it kills him?
- 他必須露面 - 即使被打死？
Next.
討論下一個問題
How could being down 12 points look like good news?
落後12個百分點不是好消息
The President was even worse weeks ago.
總統的聲望比一周前更糟
He will be out with the voters in the Midwest and then in California.
他盡可能的多接近選民 尤其是中西部 然後是加利福尼亞
The President and First Lady of the United States.
女士們先生們 美國總統和第一夫人
His Excellency, the President of France and his wife.
法國總統和第一夫人閣下到
Agent Raines, you look devastating tonight.
雷恩斯特工 今晚你漂亮極了
- Thank you. - Good enough to eat, I might add...
- 謝謝 - 足以讓人飽餐一頓啊
if you'll pardon the expression.
請原諒我的形容
I try to sympathize with you, but you really do annoy me.
知道嗎 每次我開始同情你時你總要說些讓我很生氣的話
Why sympathize?
為什麼同情我？
The tape of that phone call. When he mentioned your wife.
那段電話錄音 他說起你妻子
- Ex-wife. - At any rate, I'm sorry.
- 是前妻 - 不管是什麼 我很難過
Strange, I get sympathy from an assassin and a woman I annoy.
真奇怪 近來同情我的人除了潛在的殺手 就是我冒犯的女人
- Would you care to dance? - Perhaps some other time.
- 跳個舞好嗎？- 再說吧
I get off in a couple of hours.
兩小時後我就下班了
- What are you looking at? - Where do you hide your firearm?
- 你看什麼？- 我只是在想你把槍藏在哪兒了？
Don't tell me, let me guess.
別告訴我 讓我猜
支付總統連任競選基金5千元
詹姆斯卡尼
We're on our final approach to L.A. It's a beautiful day out there.
我們即將抵達本次航班的終點洛杉磯 天氣非常好
Thanks for flying with us. We hope to see you again.
感謝你乘坐我們的飛機 期待著再次為你服務
西南儲蓄銀行
- Deposit this in the new account. - I'll need to see your papers.
- 把這筆錢存在一個新戶上 - 我需要看一下你公司的證明文件
Microspan Corporation. What kind of business are you in?
微斯潘公司？你們是做哪類生意的？
- Software. - Up in San Jose?
- 電腦軟體 - 在聖約瑟？
I'm based there, but I'm opening an office in L.A.
總公司在那兒 我現在要在這兒洛杉磯開一個辦事處
Are you from there? Where are you from?
你是那兒的人嗎？你是哪兒人？
- Minneapolis. - You're kidding! So am I.
- 明尼波利斯 - 太巧了 我也是
Well, it's a small world.
哇 這個世界真小
I hated the winters. I used to stay in and pig out.
我討厭那兒的冬天 每年有9個月都得待在屋子裡養膘
- What high school did you go to? - New Brighton High School.
- 你上的是哪個中學？- 新布萊頓中學
- There isn't any New Brighton. - There was when I was there.
- 那兒沒有新布萊頓中學 - 噢 我在那兒時有的
Well, maybe I'm just confused. It happens a lot.
也許是我記錯了 常有這種事
- There was a school across from... - I'm late, will this take long?
- 那個中學叫什麼 - 對不起 我還要趕去開會 還要等很久嗎？
Not at all, just another minute.
不 不用 馬上就好
Thank you.
謝謝
- You have a very pleasant manner. - Thank you, Mr. Carney.
- 你有自己獨特的韻味 - 謝謝 卡尼先生
How would you like to give a colleague a ride home?
雷恩斯特工 可以讓同事搭你的車回家嗎？
- Why do you keep flirting with me? - Am I?
- 你為什麼總是挑逗我？- 我在挑逗你嗎？
- You know it can't go anywhere. - That's why I do it.
- 你知道不會有任何結果 何必？- 也許就因為我知道不會有結果
Come on, I'll buy you an ice cream. No further obligations.
走吧 捎我一段 我請你吃霜淇淋 沒有其他義務
Oh, boy.
噢 天啊
I never work with female agents before, how many are there?
我從沒跟女特工一起工作過 你們有多少人？
About 125.
大約125人
- Pure window dressing. - Excuse me?
- 純粹是裝飾門面 - 你說什麼？
Window dressing. 125 out of 2,000.
裝飾門面 2千5百特工中只有125個女性
You're around so the President looks good to his feminist voters.
他們用你們只是為讓總統吸引女性選民
- Do you make an effort to be obnoxious? - It's a gift.
- 你這討厭是後來培養的 還是天生的？- 天生的
We do a lot of window dressing. Like running with the limousine.
別不承認 我們做的一半工作是裝飾門面 就說在汽車兩旁跟著跑
It'd take an anti-tank missile to put a dent in it.
反坦克導彈也只能在上面砸個凹痕
But it makes the President look more presidential.
可我們得表演讓總統看上去更像總統
If I'm here for the feminist vote, what demographics do you represent?
如果我是為吸引女性選民 那你代表哪種類型的人？
Let us see.
這麼說
White, piano-playing, heterosexuals over the age of 50.
以喜歡彈鋼琴的50歲以上 異性戀白種男人
There ain't a lot of us, but we do have a powerful lobby.
我們人數不多 被惹火時 我們的權勢可不小
- Time flies when you're annoyed. - Where are you going?
- 當你討厭時 時間過得飛快 - 你去哪？
- I have a date. - With whom?
- 我有個約會 - 和誰？
That's none of your business.
這不關你的事
- You want a ride? - I don't think so.
- 還要我捎你一段嗎？- 不用了
I like it here this time of day. I think I'll hang out.
我喜歡這裡的黃昏 我再待一會
Okay, thanks for the ice cream.
那好吧 謝謝你的霜淇淋
- See you. - You're welcome.
- 再見 - 別客氣
If she looks back, that means she's interested.
如果她回頭 表示她喜歡我
Come on now, give me that smug look and be on your way.
回頭啊 看我一眼 給我一個得意的眼神 再接著走你的路
Well, Abe.... Damn, I wish I could've been there for you.
林肯先生？希望我能在場保護你
Hi, baby, how are you doing?
嗨 寶貝 你好嗎？
Yes, I missed you too.
真乖 我也想你
I didn't mean to startle you. I got your address from the phone book.
對不起 我不是故意嚇你一跳 我從電話薄上找到你的住址
- I'm not listed. - Well, I better come clean.
- 可我的名字不在電話薄上 - 哦 那 我只好說實話了
I followed you. I'm sorry, I'm not very good at this.
我跟蹤你 對不起 幹這種事我是外行
I'm new in town. I was wondering if you'd care to join me for dinner.
我在這 人生地不熟 不知今晚你肯不肯和我一起吃晚飯？
That's sweet, but...
我 我很高興 可是我
I also wanted to apologize for lying to you about being from Minneapolis.
我要向你道歉 我撒了謊 我們都知道我不是明尼波利思人
I shouldn't ask so many questions.
我不應該問那麼多問題
Did you mention our conversation to anyone at the bank?
你有沒有把我們今天下午在銀行的談話告訴過別人？
- No! - May I?
- 沒有 - 可以進來嗎？
Rory, settle down!
羅利 老實點 老實點
- Pam, what's going on? Oh, hi. - This is my roommate.
- 帕姆？怎麼回事？哦 嗨 - 這是我的室友
- Sally, this is Mr. Carney. - Nice to meet you.
- 賽麗 這位是卡尼先生 - 很高興認識你
- I was just on my way out. - I'm sorry, but you can't leave.
- 我剛好準備出門 - 對不起 今晚不能讓兩位小姐離開這裡
What?
什麼？
You shouldn't have been from Minneapolis.
你不應該出生在明尼波利斯
I don't know what you want, but....
卡尼先生 我不明白你想幹什麼 可是
- Hi, this is Sally. - This is Pam. We're not in right now.
- 嗨 我是賽麗 - 我是帕姆 我們不是出去玩了 就是正在睡覺
- Leave your name and number. - And we'll call you back. Bye.
- 請留下你的電話和姓名 - 我們會打給你 再見
Frank, I hope you don't mind me calling you at the office.
弗蘭克 希望你不介意我打電話到你辦公室 我就在附近
- No, why don't you drop by? - I'd love to.
- 幹嘛不過來坐坐？- 我很樂意 弗蘭克
Let me take some time to welcome those who are joining us late.
啊 我先花點時間 歡迎那些加入我們談話的人
I'd love to drop by. We've got so much in common.
我願意去拜訪你 很想去 我們有許多共同之處
We do? Like what?
是嗎？哪方面？
We are both willing to trade our lives for the President's.
我們都願用自己的命換總統的命
We were both betrayed by those we trusted.
我們都是誠實有能力的人 都被我們信任的人出賣了
- I wasn't betrayed, Booth. - Sure you were, Frank.
- 我沒被出賣 布思 - 你當然有 弗蘭克
The Warren Commission reported your procedure as seriously deficient.
沃倫委員會關於總統遇刺的報告上說你們的程式有嚴重缺陷
They criticized all the agents for being out drinking the night before.
他們批評你和其他特工在事發前一夜喝酒至深夜
As if Kennedy would be alive today if you'd been in bed by 10p.m.
似乎如果你們10點上床睡覺 甘迺迪今天也許還活著
- Maybe they were right. - No, they weren't right.
- 也許他們說的對 - 不 其實他們錯了
You wanted to have agents stationed all around his car. He refused.
你曾要求在車後和兩旁安排特工 可他拒絕了
Do you know why? Because he had a death wish.
知道他為什麼拒絕嗎？我認為他想死
He talked all the time about being assassina ted.
他生前經常談論被暗殺
His favorite poem was I Have a Rendezvous with Death...
他最喜歡的一句詩是 我和死神有個約會
which is not a good poem, Frank.
這不是一首好詩 弗蘭克
I think he wanted to die.
我認為他想死
And I think he didn't care that his death would ruin your life.
他不在乎他的死會毀了你的一生
What do you think?
你怎麼看 弗蘭克？
Frank?
弗蘭克？
- What about you? Who betrayed you? - I don't think he's scrambling it.
- 那你呢 布思？你被誰出賣了？- 我想他沒有用干擾器
Some of the same people, but I'm going to get even.
啊 同一夥人 我要報仇
I'll have my day in the sun. The question is, will you?
我會有揚眉吐氣的那一天 問題是 你會有嗎？
I think you're in for a lot more pain.
我看你還要經歷很多痛苦
How much of this shit do I have to listen to?
這種混帳話我還要聽多久？
He's across the street. LaFayette Park.
就在街對面 拉斐耶特公園 拖住他
Booth!
布思？
Are you guys crazy?
你們瘋了嗎？
I told you to get in shape, Frank.
我說過你應該鍛煉身體 弗蘭克
Is this your current address?
這是你現在的住址嗎？
And you didn't see anybody suspicious hanging around that phone booth?
有沒有看到可疑的人 在電話亭附近逗留？
That's him! Al, that's him!
就是他 艾爾 就是他
Secret Service! I'm impounding this car. He put his hand on here.
特工部警官 我們要扣留這輛車 他的手按在這裡
- We got fingerprints. - Are you all right, Frank?
- 我們得到 他的指紋 - 你沒事吧 弗蘭克？
Hey Tony, have a look at this.
嘿 托尼 你來看這個
- The print from Secret Service? - Yeah, it's really strange.
- 是特工部送來的指紋？- 對 有些不對頭
This is C-12. We can't tell them.
該死 是機密C12級 不能告訴他們
Horrigan, I'm afraid we've drawn a blank.
霍利根先生 恐怕是白忙一場
- You're sure? - We ran it against everything.
- 你肯定？- 我們查了所有存檔記錄
I'm meeting with the President. You keep investigating.
明天一早我跟總統出發 你繼續調查
- What should I do? - You'll think of something.
- 我 我該做些什麼？- 動動腦子
You're a real pain when things don't go your way.
事情沒按你的想法發展 你就特別惹人討厭 弗蘭克
Your friends warned you about that.
你的朋友早警告過你
The President hit the campaign trail today on a 6-day tour of 12 states.
總統今天開始了巡迴競選活動 踏上了旋風般的6天12州之旅
With just a month to the election, he's trailing by 10 points.
距大選還有一個月 總統仍落後他的對手10個百分點
He'll concentrate on the Midwest, where he's sagging in the polls.
他將集中精力把重點放在選票下降最多的中西部地區
The campaign will wind up in Chicago with a big rally.
此次競選活動由芝加哥一次大型集會開始
Reservations.
這裡是訂票專線
Do you have a flight on Tuesday from Washington to L.A.?
是的 有沒有星期二從華盛頓到洛杉磯的機票
I'd like an open-ended ticket so I can make some stops on my return.
回程票不定日期 返回時我可能在中西部停留
C-5, off-load the choppers first. Who's our route agent?
C-5 我們請求先卸下直升機上的東西 誰給我們帶路？
That'll be Jacqueline King.
賈桂琳金給你們帶路
This is Watts, we have arrival at 13.45.
我是沃茨 我們13點15分抵達
- Where are we keeping the cars? - Denver PD has an area for us.
- 這些車停在什麼地方？- 丹佛市警察局準備了一塊空地
This is Watts, we're ten minutes out.
警衛室 我是沃茨 我們已出來10分鐘
Here in Denver we gather today in the shadow of giants.
今天在丹佛 我們聚集在偉人的庇護之下
Brave pioneers who overcame the wilderness and carved a new nation.
當年勇敢的先驅克服了重重艱難 在荒野中開拓出一個新國家
Today we are asked to match our vision to their vision.
今天 我們必須繼承先人的遠大眼光 習守美國的未來傳下去
And to pass that legacy on.
傳給我們的孩子和孩子們的孩子
- Is sector three secure? - Sector three is secure.
- 霍利根報告3號地區一切正常 - 3號地區一切正常
The President was campaigning today in Denver.
今天總統在丹佛市展開競選活動
We are living in a time of global economic transition.
我們生活在一個全球經濟轉變的時代
We need compassion and vision to create a future...
我們需要滿腔熱情和敏銳目光 去創造未來
of peace and progress for everyone.
把和平和進步帶給每一個美國人
The President is due to arrive here in L.A. later in the month.
剛才是總統今天在內布拉斯克的演講 本月下旬他將來到洛杉磯
He'll compete for California's 54 electoral votes.
爭取加利福尼亞至關重要的54票
This is Sandy Riggs calling.
嗨 這是桑迪瑞格給詹姆斯卡尼的留言
If you want to catch a rally in the Midwest, you'd best call me.
詹姆斯如果你想趁你在中西部時出席總統的集會請給我打電話
西南銀行
The President has no fixed schedule.
總統的行程每個小時都在改變
In answer to your other question, just send a check to party headquarters.
回答你另外一個問題 請把支票寄到這裡的黨總部
Ladies and gentlemen of Holly, Michigan...
密西根的女士們先生們
the President of the United States.
美利堅合眾國 總統
We've gone a long way toward achieving that goal....
為了達到這個目標 我們已經走過了很長的路
We've got some trouble up ahead. Notify the White House staff.
沃茨 我是弗林 前面的路軌出了問題 請通知白宮人員
Milwaukee will be easy tomorrow.
明天密爾沃基會輕鬆一點
Flight 318 to Milwaukee is now boarding at Gate 21.
各位旅客請注意 飛往密爾沃基318號航班 在21號登機口開始登機了
All passengers proceed to the boarding area now.
請所有乘客前往登機口
Checking.
檢查
Hey, pal, found any bombs today?
嘿 夥計 今天找到炸彈了？
- Did the First Lady ask about me? - Have you gotten to know them yet?
- 第一夫人有沒有問起我？- 你跟他們很熟嗎？
- I prefer not to get to know them. - Why is that?
- 通常我寧願不認識我所保護的人 - 為什麼？
They might not be worth taking a bullet for.
可能會認為他們不值得你替他們擋子彈
Here comes my replacement. Let's go to the bar.
接我班的人來了 和我一起去酒吧
- We can't drink on the road. - But they have a great piano player.
- 外出執勤不許喝酒 - 當然 可那裡有個一流的鋼琴師
I've played for presidents and with presidents.
我曾為幾位總統演奏過
Nixon and I once did a duet of Moonglow.
還和尼克森合彈過二重奏 月光
- I heard he didn't like you. - We got on all right.
- 我聽說他不喜歡你 - 不是真的 我們相處得還好
His Chief of Staff didn't like me.
是他的白宮總管不喜歡我
He once ordered me to get rid of some anti-war protesters.
有一次在波士頓我們吵起來 他叫我趕走幾個反戰杭議者
I said I couldn't do that. Freedom of speech and such.
我說我不能那麼做 要知道有議論自由
He said, When I'm talking to you, I am the President.
他說 我在跟你說話 我就是總統
I said, You look like a sack of shit in a cheap suit to me, sir!
我看你更像包在廉價西服裡的臭狗屎
- The sir was a classy touch. - l thought so.
- 我喜歡這句 先生 蠻有格調的 - 我也這麼想
You never wear shades when you're standing post.
站崗時你為什麼從不戴墨鏡？
I like the wackos to see the whites of my eyes.
我喜歡讓瘋子看到我的眼睛
A glare can be just as effective as a gun. Know what I mean?
犀利的目光能像槍一樣有威懾力 明白我的意思？
Oh, yeah.
哦 明白
You know what I mean?
明白我的意思？
You got me.
我比不過你
You'd better stick to the shades, sweetheart.
你還是戴著墨鏡好 寶貝
What are you afraid of?
雷恩斯特工 你怕什麼？
I'm afraid of making a big mistake.
怕在犯一個大錯誤
Good night.
晚安
Good, we've got some updates on Milwaukee.
噢 很好 明天密爾沃基的最新日程出來了
Thanks.
謝謝
- Don't answer it. - No. Oh, shit.
- 別理它 - 不行 噢 見鬼 噢
Raines.
雷恩斯
Okay, I'll be right down.
好 我馬上下去
Traveler's losing ground in Georgia. Milwaukee's out tomorrow.
旅客在喬治亞州的希望破滅 所以明天不去密爾沃基了
And they're staging a rally somewhere outside Atlanta.
他們要去亞特蘭大附近一個地方
Damn!
噢 該死
What am I doing?
噢 我這是在幹什麼？
Oh, Lilly...
啊 莉莉
I've got to put all that shit back on, damn it!
我還得一件一件再穿上 真見鬼
I'm glad to see you all out here in the rain with me today.
今天能在這裡和大家在雨中相聚 我非常高興
I've been saying, Don't just vote for me, join me.
我總是和周圍的人說 別只是投我的票 要和我在一起
And today you certainly have. We may get a tad damp today.
今天你們做到了 今天我們雖然淋了雨
But guess who's gonna be all wet on Election Day?
不過你們猜 誰在投票那天會變成落湯雞？
How about the watch list?
監視名單怎麼樣？
Twenty-three crazies are under surveillance.
本地有23個瘋子都在監視中
The hospital?
醫院方面？
Extra units of Traveler's blood type are on hand.
額外準備旅客血型的血漿
Accessible to the alternate route too.
所有後備地點的道路也檢查過了
- Under the weather? - Sick as a dog, Lilly.
- 對氣候不適應？- 病得一塌踏糊塗 莉莉
What's this? Psychological Profile of John Booth.
這是什麼？約翰布思的心理分析
- Did you make a mistake? - What?
- 那麼 你犯錯了？- 什麼？
You said you were afraid of making a big mistake.
你在酒吧說你害怕犯大錯誤
With this job, let's be realistic. It's not like we work in a bank.
我是指工作面對現實吧 我們不是在銀行上班
- You had an affair with an agent? - He wasn't an agent.
- 這麼說你和特工談過戀愛 結果很糟糕？- 他不是特工
But he left you because you wouldn't quit your job?
那他離開你是因為你不肯放棄工作？
I left him. I wouldn't quit my job for him.
是我離開他 弗蘭克 因為我不肯為他放棄工作
It broke my heart.
我的確很傷心
You vowed never again to let a man come between you and your career.
你就發誓再不讓男人擋在你和你的工作之間？
But now you're in love with me and it scares you a little, doesn't it?
你現在愛上我 這讓你有點害怕 對嗎？
- Blow your nose. - Sorry.
- 弗蘭克 擦擦你的鼻子 - 對不起
What would happen if I gave up my job for you?
你看這樣好嗎 我為你放棄我的工作？
Why would you do that?
你幹嘛要這麼做？
I vowed never again to let my career come between me and a woman.
也許我發過誓 再不讓工作擋在我和一個女人之間
Frank.
弗蘭克
- Hey, be careful, will you? - Yeah?
- 嘿 小心點好嗎？ - 什麼？
This whole event's been advertised in advance. Just be alert.
今晚的活動已事先發佈消息 你要警惕
Watts, it's Horrigan, it's a zoo here. We gotta take Traveler underground.
沃茨 我是霍利根 這裡亂得像動物園 必須讓旅客走地下
This is Watts. We are using the alternate arrival site. Underground.
各崗位注意 我是沃茨 我們走備用路線 走地下
- Watts, Booth may be here. - l thought you couldn't identify him.
- 霍利根報告沃茨 我想布思可能在這裡 - 我想你不認識他
- I can't. Just call it a hunch. - Ignore your psychic abilities.
- 我不認識 只是我的直覺 - 我無意貶低你的心靈感應能力
All posts take to your positions.
所有人員 各就各位
- You've got a fever, Frank. - You stay alert in there, will you?
- 你在發燒 弗蘭克 - 你提高警惕 好嗎？
One quality above all marks this President.
我們的總統有一個特別突出的品質
It has earned him the respect of the people of this country.
這讓他受到全國勞動階級的愛戴
That quality is courage.
這個品質就是勇氣
The question is, will we stand by the man who has stood by us?
現在有個問題 我們是否支援這個曾經支援過我們的人
- Stage right? - Stage right, all clear.
- 安全檢查 講臺右方？- 講臺右方沒問題
- Stage left? - Stage left, clear.
- 講臺左方 - 講臺左方 正常
- Stage center? - Stage center, clear.
- 講臺中央？- 中央一切正常
The President of the United States and the First Lady!
歡迎美國總統和第一夫人
- Gun! - Get down!
- 有刺客 - 趴下
What the hell's going on in there?
這是保衛室 發生了什麼事？
All clear.
一切正常
- False alarm. - Traveler's secure. Resume positions.
- 是場虛驚 - 旅客很安全 全部返回崗位
- Are you hurt, Mr. President? - I'm all right.
- 你沒事吧 總統先生？- 我沒事 我很好
Everything's all right, folks. We had a little false alarm there.
各位 沒有事 一切都很好 只是一場虛驚
That was exciting, wasn't it? Take your seat, please.
我覺得很刺激 對嗎？女士們先生們請大家就座
It was just a balloon popping. Traveler wants to continue.
保衛室 我是雷恩斯 剛才是氣球爆裂 一切正常 旅客要繼續
Do you have any idea how many votes you cost us last night?
知道昨晚你讓總統丟掉多少選票嗎？
The President looked like a coward.
總統在全國電視上的樣子像個膽小鬼
He looked all right. You were the one who looked like a coward.
我覺得他的樣子還可以 倒是你的樣子像個該死的儒夫
- Is this just a joke to you? - No, you're a joke to me.
- 你覺得這很好笑？- 不 我覺得你很好笑 哈瑞
- You have no idea what we do. - That's enough!
- 你根本不瞭解我們的工作 - 夠了 霍利根
I'll have you busting counterfeiters in Alaska!
你再叫我一聲 哈瑞 就發配你去阿拉斯加查偽鈔
Keep him away from the White House and away from me!
你別讓他再靠近總統靠近白宮 當然也不許他靠近我
- The man's a disgrace. - You can't talk to him like that.
- 這傢伙真給特工部丟人 - 你不能這樣跟白宮總管說話
I don't work for him.
我又不為他工作
You work for me. At least you did. You're off my detail.
可你為我工作 至少曾經是 你不再是我的部下了
My Super Bowl debt. In case I don't see you after this trip.
這是超級杯輸你的錢 萬一回去後見不到你了
You know, Frank...
你也知道 弗蘭克
if you just acknowledge that it was an unfortunate situation.
如果你肯承認 那只是一次不愉快的事件
- I'm not going to apologize. - I'm not saying you should.
- 我不會為自己盡了責任而道歉 - 我沒說你不對
- But the President was humiliated. - He's alive.
- 可畢竟 總統也很丟人 - 至少他還活著 對嗎？
- We are here to save his dignity too. - I'm not paid for that.
- 我們同時也要保護他的尊嚴 - 那不是我的職責
When Kennedy's girlfriend got into trouble, you said she was with you.
甘迺迪的情婦在白宮被抓住時 你說她是你的女友
- That was just a rumor. - I heard the whole story.
- 別人跟你說什麼你全都相信 - 弗蘭克 王爾德都告訴我了
You were suspended for a month in order to save his dignity.
為那件事你被停薪反省一個月 我說那是為了保護總統尊嚴
- He was different. - Maybe you were different.
- 那不一樣 他不一樣 - 也許是你不一樣了
I was different. The whole country was different.
我是不一樣了 整個國家都不一樣了
Everything would be different if I'd been half as paranoid as I am today.
如果當初我有今天一半反應過度 一切都會是另一個樣子
Frank.
弗蘭克
Why not just retire? Live off your pension. What's the point?
乾脆退休算了 弗蘭克 靠退休金生活幹下去又能怎麼樣？
Somebody else asked me that not long ago.
不久前有人也問過我這個問題
You don't spend any money, except on jazz records.
除了買爵士樂唱片你沒有別的開銷
I want to stay on the Booth case, Sam.
我要繼續調查布思的案子
All right, but as for protective detail
好吧 不過當貼身待衛的事
I understand.
我明白
That thing in Chicago....
芝加哥發生的事
I've never been on the wrong side of a judgment call like that.
我想不通 以前從沒犯過這種判斷上的錯誤
You had the flu! That can impair your judgment.
你生病了 誰都知道那會影響判斷力
Face it, Frank. You're too old for this shit.
面對現實吧 弗蘭克 幹這行你太老了
Hello.
喂？
What happened in the Windy City, Frank?
在芝加哥你是怎麼了 弗蘭克？
Booth?
布思？
- Did the balloon get you panicky? - You were there.
- 氣球讓你慌了手腳？- 你也在場
Yes, yes.
對對 我也在
I couldn't help wondering why you'd risk your life to save such a man.
看著總統 我禁不住想為什麼你這種人願意冒生命危險保護他？
You have such a strange job. I can't decide if it's heroic or absurd.
你的工作很奇怪 不知是英雄還是荒謬
Why would you risk your life to kill a man like that?
那為什麼你這種人願意 冒生命危險殺掉他？
- Read my psychological profile. - I don't believe in them.
- 沒看過我的心理測試報告嗎？- 我不相信這些東西
Nor do I. A man's actions don't equal the sum of his psychological parts.
我也不信 一個人的行為不等於他心理的總和
- It doesn't work that way. - Just how does it work?
- 這種方法不對 - 那怎麼樣才對？
It doesn't work. God doesn't punish the wicked and reward the righteous.
根本沒有辦法 弗蘭克 惡未必有惡報 善也未必有善報
Everyone dies. Some die because they deserve to.
人人都會死 有些人死因為他該死
Others die because they come from Minneapolis. It's meaningless.
有些人死只因為他們出生在明尼波利斯 完全是巧合 毫無意義
If none of this means anything, why kill the President?
嗯 如果這些毫無意義 為什麼要暗殺總統？
- To punctuate the dreariness. - You need to get yourself laid.
- 為了強調它的單調乏味 - 我覺得你需要給自己找個女人 布思
You're the same. Name one thing in your life that has any meaning.
你和我一樣 弗蘭克 說說你生活裡哪些事有意義
- l play the piano. - That's not enough.
- 我會彈鋼琴 - 這可不夠
How do you know? Do you play?
你怎麼知道？你會彈嗎？
I've seen you in your bar alone.
我看見你在酒吧獨坐
There's no cause worth fighting for. All we have is the game.
生活中已沒有值得為之奮鬥的目標 我們都在玩這個遊戲
- I'm on offense. You're on defense. - When do we start playing the game?
- 由我進攻 由你防守 - 我們什麼時候開始玩的？
The clock's ticking, Frank. Take care.
計時已經開始 弗蘭克 多保重
Wait. Wait, Booth.
等等 等等 布思
He scrambled it. I missed him.
弗蘭克？他又用了干擾器 我沒查到
Fuck!
見鬼
Fucker.
Jesus, Frank.
天哪 弗蘭克
I called for hours. I thought something happened to you.
我打了一小時電話 還以為你出事了
I'm sick, I'm tired and I'm armed, too. So be careful.
我不好 又病 又累 身上還有槍 你要當心
- You're also maybe a genius. - Not to be recognized in this lifetime.
- 你還可能是個天才 - 這輩子還沒人稱讚過我
- Did you listen to the call? - Yeah, remember?
- 你聽過剛才的電話了？- 是 還記得你說過
Call the field office in Minneapolis.
你馬上和明尼波利斯分部聯絡
See what you can find about accidental deaths.
查查有沒有意外死亡或謀殺
Frank! Will you listen to me, please?
弗蘭克 你聽我說好嗎？
- Spit it out, damn it! - We spoke to some model builders.
- 快說吧 該死的 - 你說過讓各地特工調查汽車模型？
There is a professor at Pasadena College. I think we've got something.
加州帕薩丹納美術設計學校有個教授 我想他有線索
I met him at a design conference in New Orleans a year ago.
一年前在新奧爾良的一個設計大會上遇見他
We ordered a few rounds of drinks. He seemed like a nice enough guy.
在飯店的酒吧裡喝了幾杯 他看上去人不錯
But when we talked politics he got a nasty edge.
可是話題轉到政治時 他突然變得很暴躁
He said the government betrayed him and he was out for revenge.
說這個政府背叛了他 他要採取極端手段進行報復
The way he said it scared me.
他說話的樣子讓我很害怕
I said, Nice talking to you. And I got the hell out of there.
所以我對他說 好吧 很高興認識你 祝你好運 我就趕緊走了
For the life of me I cannot remember his name.
我真的不記得他叫什麼名字
But I'm pretty sure he said he was from Phoenix.
不過可以肯定他說他住在鳳凰城
You ought to talk to a guy in Phoenix named Walter Wickland.
知道你們該找誰嗎？鳳凰城有個人叫沃爾特威克蘭
- We're going to Phoenix. - Let's get a police artist.
- 馬上訂去鳳凰城的機票 - 找個警方畫家根據教授的描述
- Have a sketch faxed to us. - You figured that out by yourself?
- 畫張素描傳給我們怎麼樣？- 這是你自己想出來 艾爾？
- Kiss my ass, Frank. - I told you you'd make a good agent.
- 去你的吧 弗蘭克？- 我說過你會成為好特工
That doesn't look much like him, but it's got to be Mitch Leary.
不是特別像 但肯定是米奇 米奇利瑞
- I haven't seen him in over a year. - What do you know about the guy?
- 我一年多沒見到他了 - 對他你瞭解多少？
You see this wheelchair? Mitch bought it for me.
看見這輪椅嗎？是米奇給我買的
It cost over $1,000.
1千多元
- You see this? - Take it easy now.
- 看這個？- 哇 哇 小心點
This is in case he ever comes back.
這是為了防止他再回來
He accused me of ripping off his design.
他譴責我偷了他設計的一個模型
He said my penalty for disloyalty was death.
說我背叛他的下場是死刑
If you put him away, I'll sleep better.
抓住他後 告訴我一聲 我會睡得安穩些
- Where can we find him? - I've got his address somewhere.
- 知道在哪兒能找到他？- 我想還能找到他的地址
Don't move.
不許動
Drop it!
放下
- Let him go, Horrigan. - I got him.
- 放開他 霍利根 - 他跑不了
It's okay. We're on the same team.
別緊張 都是自己人 自己人
- Hands, motherfucker! - I'm getting my identification!
- 舉起手 把手舉起來 - 我給你們看證件
- Give it to me. - David Coppinger. CIA.
- 遞給我 - 大衛科平傑 中情局
- And who's this asshole? - He's with me.
- 這個混蛋是誰？- 是我的人
- Goddamn it! - Are you here for Leary or me?
- 真他媽的 - 你在這兒等誰？利瑞還是我？
Mr. Leary used to be one of our operatives.
利瑞曾經為中央情報局工作過
- He's threatened to kill the President. - We didn't think he was serious.
- 你們知道他威脅要刺殺總統？- 原來以為他只是說說而已
- But you knew. You and the FBI. - I understand your frustration.
- 你們和調查局早就知道 - 你的氣憤我能理解
You understand my frustration? You pompous son of a bitch!
你理解我的氣憤？你們這些混蛋
What did Leary do for you? Run drugs? Sell arms to Iran?
利瑞為你們幹什麼？替反政府人士販毒 還是賣軍火給伊朗？
It's a C-12 matter, so this is off the record.
這是C-12機密 所以 私下說吧
If asked, I'm going to deny it.
如果被問我會否認
- Leary's what we call a wet boy. - What's a wet boy, Frank?
- 利瑞是我們局裡的 濕小子 - 什麼是濕小子 弗蘭克？
- Leary's an assassin. - He's more like a predator.
- 利瑞是個殺手 - 他更像個食肉動物
- Was that you shooting? - Yes.
- 剛才是你開的槍？- 是的
- What kind of gun is that? - Something I made.
- 你那是什麼槍？- 是我自己造的
You made it? That beats paying for it.
你造的？比買的還好用？
- Can I see it? - Yeah.
- 我可以看看嗎？- 好
- It's light. What's it made of? - It's composite. Like plastic.
- 哇 這麼輕 用什麼做的？- 一種複合物有點像塑膠
Pretty neat! Mind if I give her a little dance?
真棒 你介意我試一下嗎？
- Not at all. - Go for it.
- 一點不 - 打一槍
That is great! That is really great!
太棒了 太棒了
- Would you sell it? - No, I need it.
- 你有沒有興趣賣掉它？- 不 我自己要用
- For what? - To assassinate the President.
- 幹什麼用？- 刺殺美國總統
- Why would you want to do that for? - Why did you kill that bird, asshole?
- 你為什麼要殺他 先生？- 你為什麼要殺那只鳥 混蛋？
Leary was one of our most effective contractors, but times changed.
米奇利瑞是我們最能幹的合同人員之一 可時代和政治氣候變了
Cutbacks had to be made. Leary didn't take it too well.
裁員是不可避免的 利瑞接受不了無法調整回去過正常生活
- We've not been able to locate him. - We can work together on this.
- 我們找了他很久 - 如果我們聯手 可能性就大許多
- Wouldn't that be refreshing? - We have fingerprints and photos.
- 這可真令人振作 - 我們有他的指紋 還有這麼多照片
- These are at least 15 years old. - He's camera-shy.
- 這些照片至少是15年前拍的 - 幹他這行總是躲著鏡頭
He'll be in disguise, anyway. We need photo alterations, Sam.
根本沒用 反正他會化妝 我看需要修改照片 山姆
What I'm about to show you is highly classified.
先生們 下面要給你們看的要絕對保密
This is a former colleague of Leary's. A close friend.
這個人是利瑞的同事 他們是好朋友
He went by Leary's home to try and get him to accept counseling.
他去利瑞鳳凰城的家想勸利瑞接受心理治療和再培訓
This is how Leary treats his friends.
這就是利瑞對待朋友的方法
We need every possible variable. Facial hair, glasses, weight change.
我們需要各種可能的相貌 鬍子 皮膚顏色 眼鏡 體重改變
Keep in mind he's 15 years older now.
記住 他比照片老15歲
As good as they are, they aren't much good. The eyes are dead.
還不錯 但不夠逼真 眼神沒顯出來
You can always tell a man by his eyes.
人的眼睛最能說明問題
- Tomorrow morning I'd like you to... - I'm resigning tomorrow.
- 聽著 我要你明天早上 - 明天我要辭職 弗蘭克
What?
什麼？
What for? Because you were scared down in Phoenix? I was scared too.
為什麼？就因為在鳳凰城把你嚇著了？其實我也嚇得要死
I have nightmares about that boat with the bag over my head.
我不斷地做噩夢 弗蘭克 夢見我頭上罩著塑膠袋
I can't breathe. Phoenix clinched it.
我喘不過氣 鳳凰城的事讓我下了決心
- The service has counselors. - I've been to counselors.
- 處裡有專門的心理醫生 - 我找過他們了 弗蘭克
- We can get this guy. - l can't do it!
- 我需要你 我們能抓住這傢伙 - 我辦不到
Stop this cockamamie shit. Come on, pal, I need you.
別哭爹喊娘了 行不行？別這樣 我需要你
Please.
求你了
Okay, Frank.
好吧 弗蘭克
Cockamamie. That's a word your generation hasn't embraced yet.
哭爹喊娘 這個詞你們年輕一代已經不用了
You ought to use it once in a while to keep it alive.
也許你可以偶爾用一下 別讓它失傳了
- Cockamamie! - Yeah.
- 哭爹喊娘？- 對
- Oh, God! - Well, it made you laugh.
- 噢 天啊 - 它讓你笑了 老天爺
You kill me, Frank.
笑死我了 弗蘭克
Hello.
喂？
Hello, Frank. And let me welcome all of you joining our program.
你好 弗蘭克 先歡迎在旁邊偷聽的人加入我們的遊戲
I know who you are, Leary.
我知道你是誰了 利瑞
I'm glad. Friends should be able to call each other by name.
我很高興 弗蘭克 朋友之間就應該稱呼名字
- We're not friends. - Sure, we are.
- 我們不是朋友 - 我們當然是
I've seen what you do to friends.
我見過你怎樣對待朋友
- What's that supposed to mean? - You slit your friend's throat.
- 你這話是什麼意思？- 你割斷了朋友的喉嚨
- You talked to Coppinger? - Yeah.
- 你跟科平傑談過了 弗蘭克？- 對 是的
Did you de-louse? The man's a professional liar.
你被洗腦了？那傢伙是個職業騙子
I saw the photos.
我見到了照片
No, you saw what he wanted you to see.
不 你看到的是他們想讓你看到的
I saw a picture of your friend with his throat cut.
照片上你的朋友躺在地上喉嚨被割斷
What you don't know is that they sent my best friend...
可你沒看見 弗蘭克 你不可能知道 他們派我最好的朋友
to my home to kill me!
我的生死同志 到我家裡來要殺掉我
- Your voice is shaking. - I haven't lied to you, Frank!
- 你的聲音在顫抖 - 我不會騙你 弗蘭克 永遠不會
Everyone who ever knew you says you're sick.
為什麼認識你的人 都說是個神經錯亂的混蛋？
- Your colleagues. Your wife. - What does your wife say about you?
- 你的同事 你的妻子 - 你妻子是怎麼說你的 弗蘭克？
Frank, I want you to understand.
弗蘭克 所有人當中我只想讓你明白
We both used to think that this country was a very special place.
因為我們都曾經認為這個國家是個特殊的地方
Do you have any idea what I've done for God and country?
你知道我為這個國家幹了什麼？
Some horrible things!
都是些相當可怕的事
I don't even remember who I was before they got their claws into me.
我甚至不記得他們的魔爪伸向我之前 我究竟是誰
- They made you into a real monster. - And now they want to destroy me.
- 他們把你變成了野獸 對嗎？- 現在他們想消滅我
What do you see when you're in the dark and the demons come?
每當後半夜魔鬼再現時 你看見什麼？
I see you standing over the grave of another dead President.
我看見你 弗蘭克 看見你站在另一個總統的墳墓上
- That's not gonna happen. - Fuck you, Frank.
- 不會出這種事 我能抓住你 - 去你的 弗蘭克
I'm willing to trade my life for his and that's all it takes.
我願意一命換一命 我很聰明 我心甘情願這就足夠了
That President is coming home from California in a box.
總統一定會躺在盒子裡 從加利福尼亞回來
- Where in California? - The address?
- 加利福尼亞什麼地方？- 啊？你想要地址？
I'll keep you in the game, but I won't throw it for you.
得了 弗蘭克 我會繼續跟你玩 但我不會讓著你
- I want you to give yourself up. - To live a long and fruitful life?
- 我想讓你投降自首 - 然後長命百歲？
Don't lie to me. I have a rendezvous with death.
得了吧 弗蘭克 別騙我了 我和死神有個約會
So does the President. And so do you, if you get too close.
總統也一樣 還有你 弗蘭克 如果你太靠近的話
You have a rendezvous with my ass, motherfucker!
你和狗屁有個約會 混帳王八蛋
You know how easily I could kill you?
弗蘭克 弗蘭克 知道我要想殺你是多麼容易嗎？
I've watched you go home.
知道多少次我看著你進出你的公寓？
You are alive because I have allowed you to live.
你還活著是因為我讓你活著
Show me some damn respect!
所以你最好對我尊重一點
St. Francis Hotel!
聖佛朗西斯飯店
Frank.
弗蘭克
Take my hand, Frank.
抓住我的手 弗蘭克
Take it. If you don't, you'll die.
抓住它不然你會摔死
Take it.
來吧
You're gonna shoot me after I saved your life?
你要打死我 弗蘭克？我剛救了你的命？
Shit.
該死
The only way to save the President is to shoot me.
救總統的唯一辦法就是殺了我
Are you willing to trade your life for his...
你願意這麼做嗎？用你的死換他的活？
or is life too precious?
還是生命太寶貴？
Leary, don't move!
利瑞 站住不許動
I got him!
弗蘭克？我抓住他了
Al?
艾爾？
There's nothing here.
這裡沒有什麼
Frank, you've got a phone call.
弗蘭克 你的電話
Yeah?
喂
Frank, you looked so sad on the bus. I'm sorry, it was self-defense.
你在公共汽車上的樣子很淒涼 對不起 我是自衛
- Tell me about Skellum. - Skellum is worthless.
- SKELLUM是什麼？- 你搞錯了方向 這個字沒有意思
- Are you gonna meet him in L.A.? - You're way behind in the game.
- 你跟他在洛杉磯見面？- 太晚了 弗蘭克 你落後我很多
I'm way ahead. I know what you look like. I've seen your eyes.
我在你前面 利瑞 我知道你的長相 我看見了你的眼睛
- They might look different next time. - Not what's behind them.
- 下次我的眼睛會不一樣 - 你的眼神不會變
- You better pray I never find you. - You want to kill me, Frank?
- 快祈禱別讓我找到你 混蛋 - 怎麼？你真想殺我 弗蘭克？
That's right.
一點不錯
- The irony's so thick here. - There is no irony!
- 太具諷刺性 小心被噎住 - 沒有什麼可諷刺的
The same government that trained me to kill, trained you to protect.
同一個政府訓練我殺人 訓練你去保護
Now you want to kill me. Up on that roof I protected you.
可現在你想殺掉我 可我在屋頂上保護了你
They'll write books about us.
他們會為我們寫本書 弗蘭克
- I'm tired of your bullshit! - Don't be a poor sport.
- 你的廢話我聽夠了 米奇 - 別輸不起 弗蘭克
You could have taken me out, but you chose to save your ass.
你本來可以殺掉我 可你選擇了保自己的命
It does make me wonder about Dallas.
這讓我想起了達拉斯
Did you really do all you could, or did you make a choice there too?
你真的盡了全力保護甘迺迪？還是也選擇了保護自己？
Do you really have the guts to take a bullet?
你真的有勇氣檔住子彈嗎 弗蘭克？
I'll be thinking about that when I'm pissing on your grave.
我在你墳頭上尿完尿再想這問題
There's no one named Skellum in all of Los Angeles?
洛杉磯沒有叫斯蓋勒姆的人嗎？
- What about Louisiana? - Hang on.
- 洛杉磯 也許是路易斯安那 - 傑克正在查 等一下
No Skellums. Sorry.
弗蘭克？沒有這個人 抱歉
Damn it!
媽的 該死
- The election's in three weeks. - Just stay out of California.
- 離投票還有3個星期 - 我只叫你別去加利福尼亞
If this guy's so smart, he's not gonna tell you where he'll do it.
如果這傢伙那麼聰明 就不會跑出來告訴你行刺的地點
I don't think he'd lie to me.
我想他不會騙我
You've become that close?
真有意思 你們兩個變得這麼親密？
California is the key to the whole race.
聽著 各位 加利福尼亞是整個競選的關鍵
- We can't let up now. - We have to change our procedure.
- 現在不能放棄 - 那我們只好改變計畫
- Frisk people within 50 yards. - At $10,000 dinners?
- 距他50碼以內的人都要搜身 - 那些人花1萬元買一個座位
- You're overreacting. - If I don't, the President's dead.
- 你又反應過份了 霍利根 - 我若不反應過度 總統早死了
- Why is he even here? - He's heading this investigation.
- 他怎麼還在這兒？- 弗蘭克負責調查此案
Then let him investigate, but keep him out of sight.
那就讓他調查 只要別讓總統看見他
If you'll excuse me, I'm in the middle of a campaign.
對不起失陪了 選舉的事還有一大堆
- Frank. Hi. - Hi.
- 弗蘭克 - 嗨
- Up late? - L.A. will be a lot of work.
- 在加班？- 負責洛杉磯先遣組
- What's up? - I've got a request.
- 有事嗎？- 有個請求
I'd like you to talk to Watts. Get me on your team.
請你和沃茨談談 讓我加入你的先遣組
- He thinks you'll overreact. - What do you think?
- 他認為你反應過度 - 你怎麼認為？
- You're too close to all this. - That's why I've got to be there.
- 我認為你對這事牽連太多 弗蘭克 - 所以我必須在場 莉莉
- I can spot him. Anticipate him. - You think he'll be in California?
- 我能認出他 我能攔住他 - 你真的認為他會去加利福尼亞
- Why would he tip you off? - He wants to keep the game close.
- 他幹嘛要給我們暗示？- 他想讓遊戲更刺激
This has nothing to do with you and me. Strictly professional.
這和你我個人無關 完全是公事
But that son of a bitch killed my partner. My friend.
那個雜種殺了我的搭檔 我的朋友
I know. I'm sorry.
我知道 我很難過
You're looking at a living legend.
你面前是個傳奇人物 莉莉
The only active agent who ever lost a President.
唯一沒保住總統的在職特工
Please.
幫個忙
Mr. Horrigan, welcome to Los Angeles.
歡迎來洛杉磯 霍利根先生
Can the President close the gap in the little time he has left?
總統能否趕上和對手之間保持的微小差距
Today he's in California for a rally at the Bona venture Hotel.
回答就在加利福尼亞 總統將出席在洛杉磯波拿文徹飯店舉辦的集會
Field office, the advance team is at the Bona venture.
我是察維茲 先遺組已抵達波拿文徹
- Any problems? - No.
- 有問題嗎？- 沒有
We've swept the motorcade route.
保衛中心 我是TSD 西面車隊行進路線檢查完畢
Manholes are secured. Mailboxes removed. Abandoned vehicles towed.
地下井口封閉 郵筒移走 廢棄車輛拖走 橋樑設人把守
We'll need sharpshooters on both those towers.
兩側高樓上需要佈置狙擊手
Other polls today had the President three points behind.
新的調查表明目前總統只落後3個百分點
He'll have to close that margin in California.
如果他想趕上唯一的希望 就是加州之行
Welcome to Los Angeles International Airport.
歡迎光臨洛杉磯國際機場
- Raines, double-checking those exits? - Yes, this is the third time now.
- 雷恩斯 我是霍利根 出口都檢查過了？- 是的 弗蘭克 這是第3遍了
Alert, section five.
監視名單 保羅拉比克 黃色 5號地區
Secret Service.
特工部
- Robert Stermer. - He's a bellboy. He's cleared.
- 羅伯特斯特默？- 他是行李員 已經審查過了
- Robert, have a nice day. - No questions.
- 羅伯特 祝你愉快 - 無可奉告
Come on, pack it up and move.
都走吧 滾遠點
Mr. Carney, all set.
卡尼先生？都辦好了
Finally we meet! You are James Carney?
我們終於見面了 你是詹姆斯卡尼先生？
- You must be Sandy Riggs. - So you really do exist.
- 你一定是桑迪瑞格？- 我開始懷疑是不是真有你這個人
- I'm very much human. - Let's go up to the bar.
- 我只是一個普通人 - 那好 我們去喝一杯吧
- When does the President arrive? - Tomorrow, before dinner.
- 總統什麼時候到？- 啊 明天晚上 正好趕上晚宴
Here's an invitation. Don't lose it. The Secret Service is acting crazy.
這是你的請柬 別弄丟了 為這些事特工部都快把我逼瘋了
You've got a great seat, just across from the President.
我給你安排了個好座位離總統非常近
So what is Microspan Corporation all about?
告訴我 詹姆斯 微斯潘公司是做什麼的？
I just came to meet the President. I won't bore you with business.
我只是來見總統的 瑞格先生 不想拿我公司的事把你悶壞了
I don't blame you. I don't understand high-tech.
我不怪你 我唯一不懂的就是高科技
I can't wait to introduce you. Look at this beautiful view.
真想早點把你介紹給總統 你看外面的景色多美
Yes, very pretty.
唔 確實很美
Give me the list of dinner guests. Who was the organizer?
有晚宴的客人名單嗎？誰是主辦人？
Sanford Riggs of the California Victory Fund.
桑福德瑞格 加州勝利基金會主席
Call LAPD and make sure they have no uniforms missing.
對了 給洛杉磯警察局打個電話 確認沒有丟失警服
- It's been taken care of. - Call the hospital about blood.
- 已經有人問過了 - 還有 看看醫院是否準備了充足的B型血漿
Your average American businessman who looks at product marketing...
一般美國生意人的眼睛 只盯著產品銷售計畫
sees the length and width of it. The Japanese see the depth.
你們看的是長度和寬度 可日本人看到的是深度 是長遠效益
We plan the next fiscal quarter. They plan the next quarter century.
我們只看下一個季度 日本人看到未來25年
- Our people don't understand that. - Mr. Riggs, can I talk to you?
- 應該讓我們的人民明白這點 - 瑞格先生？能佔用你一分鐘嗎？
- Who's that? - Secret Service agent.
- 那人是誰？- 特工部警探
- Do you know all these people? - l sure do.
- 參加晚宴的每個客人你都認識嗎？- 當然認識
- How about these pictures here? - I went through all this yesterday.
- 看看這些照片 有沒有面熟的 - 昨天另一個警官已經給我看過了
I'll cooperate, but this is bordering on harassment.
我很樂意合作 可這種騷擾真的讓人心煩
I'm a harassing kind of guy.
對 我這個人專門讓人心煩 瑞格先生
No, no, no, no.
不 不
I'll be right back, Mr. Carney.
我馬上過來 卡尼先生
He did what anyone of us would.
比爾 他做了我們都會做的事
He beat up a bellboy on television. I'd say he was overwrought.
他在電梯上毆打行李員 他那是緊張過度
We're all overwrought. Leary's out there someplace.
對 知道利瑞就在附近 我們都有點緊張過度
- You do not think he is a liability? - No.
- 你不覺得他是個負擔嗎？- 不 我不覺得他是負擔
Well, you're in the minority. I want him gone.
你是少數 他得在旅客到達前走
- Send him on to San Diego. - By whose order?
- 天一亮就讓他去聖地牙哥 - 這是誰的命令？哈瑞薩金特？
Traveler. Do you want to tell him or should I?
旅客 是你告訴他 還是我來？
Miss Raines, somebody's approaching Traveler's suite.
雷恩斯小姐 有人走近旅客的套房
- Hi. - Hi.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- What are you doing up here? - Seeing what I could do.
- 你在這兒幹什麼 弗蘭克？- 只是看看還有什麼我能做的
Between the LAPD, the FBI and the rest of us...
你知道 洛杉磯警察局 聯邦調查局和我們
there are 229 people protecting Traveler tomorrow.
明天共有229人保護旅客
A lot of guns.
很多槍
If Leary gets off a shot, we could be killed in the crossfire.
天啊 利瑞一開槍 你我可能不知被誰的子彈打死
Frank.
弗蘭克
- Bill Watts just called. - Heard about the bellman?
- 比爾沃茨來過電話 - 聽說行李員的事了？
So did Traveler.
旅客也聽說了
They want you to go to San Diego and assist in the advance.
他們要你明天去聖地牙哥 幫助那裡的先譴組
Just like that.
我就知道
It's not just you against Leary.
弗蘭克 不是你一個人在和利瑞鬥爭
Have some faith in the rest of us.
你要對我們其他人有點信心
You know something?
你知道嗎？
For years I've been listening to all these idiots...
這些年來 我一直聽著那些白癡高談闊論
with their pet theories on Dallas.
各種有關甘迺迪遇刺的各種理論
It was the Cubans, or the CIA.
是古巴人或中情局
The white supremacists, or the mob.
或白人至上主義分子或黑社會
Whether it was one weapon or whether it was five.
不管是1枝槍還是5枝槍
None of that meant too much to me.
這些對我都沒什麼意義
But Leary.
可是 利瑞
He questioned whether I had the guts to take that fatal bullet.
他問我是否有膽量 擋住那顆致命的子彈
God, that was a beautiful day.
那天天氣好極了
The sun was out.
下了一天雨
It had been raining all morning.
太陽出來了 空氣
The first shot sounded like a firecracker.
第一槍聽上去就像鞭炮
I looked over and saw him. I could tell he was hit.
我一抬眼看見他 我知道他中彈了
I don't know why I didn't react.
不知為什麼我沒反應
I should've reacted. I should've been running.
我應該採取行動 應該馬上撲過去
I just couldn't believe it.
我真不敢相信
If only I'd reacted, I could've taken that shot.
如果動作快 可能替他挨那一槍
It would've been all right with me.
我很願意那麼做
- What's the number in San Diego? - 619 ukulele.
- 聖地牙哥辦公室的電話號碼？- 619-UKELLE
- Ukulele? - That's how I remember it.
- UKELLE - 我記電話號碼的方法 7個數位7個字母
You just push U-K-E-L-E-L-E.
只要按U-K-E-L-E-L-E 簡單
- Ukulele? Isn't that U-K-U? - I don't know.
- 等一下 拼法不是UKU嗎？- 我不知道
But the phone number is U-K-E-L-E-L-E.
我說的是電話按鍵上的字母 U-K-E-L-E-L-E
U-K-E-L. Wait a second.
U-K-E-L 等一下
Jesus.
天哪
We have an arrival. Chopper standing by.
我們已抵達 旅客將乘直升機去1號地點
- Southwest Savings, may I help you? - Southwest?
- 西南儲蓄銀行 你好 - 西南？
- Yes. May I help you? Hello? - What's your address?
- 是的 有什麼要我幫忙的嗎？- 你們的地址是什麼？
Taxi!
計程車
- Post check. Post 3? - In place.
- 一樓大廳點名 3號位？- 收到 就位
- Post 6? - In place.
- 6號位？- 收到 就位
- Post 12? - In place.
- 12號位？- 收到 就位
Wait right here.
在這兒等我
There's no Leary in our accounts.
對不起 我們沒有叫米切爾利瑞的顧客
Try to imagine him in disguise. A hat, wigs, that sort of thing.
設想他化妝後的樣子 戴帽子 假髮 鬍子 等等
- I haven't been here long. - Who was here before you?
- 我沒見過他 我是兩個星期前新來的 - 你來之前誰負責開戶？
- Pam Magnus. - Where can I find her?
- 帕姆瑪格紐斯 - 在哪兒能找到她？
She's dead. She was murdered.
她死了 是被謀殺的
- She was murdered. - They won't cancel.
- 莉莉 她被人謀殺 她是明尼波利斯人 - 他們不會取消
- Then make the arrival underground. - They want a big show.
- 至少讓車隊走地下 別給利瑞當靶子 - 他們想造聲勢
- We need proof. - The proof may just be a dead president?
- 除非你有證據利瑞在這兒 - 證據可能是總統的屍體
I'm pulling up all the accounts Pam made, but it'll take time.
我正調出半年來帕姆經手的新開戶頭 列清單要花點時間
Fax me the list as soon as you get them.
出來後馬上發傳真給我
All agents in position.
全體人員就位
- Please step back. - Empty your pockets.
- 請退 先生 - 請把口袋內的東西拿出來
Thank you.
謝謝
You're from Texas, right?
你是德克薩斯人嗎？
Ladies and gentlemen, the President of the United States.
女士們先生們 美國總統到
I'm sorry?
你說什麼？
Frank! Watts is gonna shit if he sees you!
弗蘭克 你怎麼在這兒？沃茨看見你一定會發火
- Have you got a fax for me? - Yeah, what is it? What's this about?
- 有沒有我的傳真？- 有 剛收到 怎麼回事？
What the hell is going on, Frank?
到底出了什麼事？
James Carney.
詹姆斯卡尼
Carney, James.
卡尼 詹姆斯
- Jesus. - Frank!
- 天啊 - 弗蘭克
- What the hell is he doing here? - l don't know.
- 他怎麼會在這兒？- 不知道
- Who gave you permission... - He's here. His name is Carney.
- 霍利根 是誰允許你來的 - 他就在這兒 他叫詹姆斯卡尼
- I want the seating chart. - Give him the chart.
- 快把座點陣圖給我 - 給他吧
Gun!
有刺客
Stop! Put the gun down!
把槍放下
Get down!
趴下
Don't shoot!
別開槍
Get him in the car!
快上車
Hold your fire!
狙擊手不許開槍
Get out of his way!
快閃開
He's got a hostage!
他抓了個人質
Raines to shooters. If you have a shot, take it.
我是雷恩斯 狙擊手有機會就開槍
Nice view.
景色很美
- What's the plan, captain? - It's your man. You tell me.
- 怎麼辦 警長？- 上面是你的人 你說了算
Get me sharpshooters on the north and west towers.
讓狙擊手上西塔樓和北塔樓
Take the subject out.
消滅目標
You had the guts. You took the bullet.
看來 你有這膽量 你接了我的子彈
- l broke my damn ribs. - Sorry, I wasn't aiming at you.
- 我的肋骨斷了 - 對不起 我瞄準的不是你
Where the hell are the shooters?
狙擊手都跑哪兒去了？
- West tower in place. No lights. - No shot from the north.
- 西塔樓就位 裡面沒有燈光 - 南塔樓找不到射擊點
A bullet-proof vest is a bit of a cheat.
穿著防彈背心 弗蘭克？你作弊
- Otherwise, you played a good game. - It's no game, Leary.
- 除此之外 這遊戲你玩得不錯 - 這不是遊戲 利瑞
I was doing my job. What do we do now?
這是我的職責 現在我們怎麼辦？
Do you believe in the nobility of suicide?
你認為自殺是保持尊嚴的行為嗎？
No.
不
But if you want to blow your head off, be my guest.
但如果你想打爛你的頭 我不管 請隨便
Nicely put, but I don't want to leave this world alone.
說的好 弗蘭克 只是我不想孤獨地離開這個悲慘世界
- West tower, do you have a shot? - Negative, too dark. Target unclear.
- 西塔樓 有機會開槍嗎？- 不行 太黑了 看不見目標
- It's better to die with a friend. - Friend? You're a damn killer!
- 最好和朋友一起死 - 朋友？你是該死的殺手 該死的瘋子
I saved your life. You owe me.
別這樣跟我說話 我救過你的命 你欠我的
- I don't owe you shit. - I was always honest with you.
- 我什麼也不欠你 - 我對你一直是誠實公平的
- Go ahead and shoot. - It's Frank. Quiet!
- 動手吧 開槍 - 是弗蘭克 安靜
- Come on. - Are you talking to me?
- 開槍吧 見鬼 - 弗蘭克 你在跟我說話？
- What are you waiting for? - Waiting for?
- 你還等什麼？- 我在等什麼？
I'm waiting for some gratitude.
我在等你向我表示感謝
Without me, you're a sad-eyed, piano- playing drunk.
沒有我你至今還是個會彈鋼琴的酒鬼
I brought you into this game. I let you keep up with me.
是我把你帶進這個遊戲 我讓你跟上我
- I made you a hero today. - You didn't make me anything.
- 今天我把你造就成英雄 - 你沒有造就我什麼
I redeemed your pathetic life.
我挽救了你可悲的生活
I just did my job. You're the one with a pathetic life.
我盡了我的職責 你才過著可悲的生活
- Go ahead and shoot! - If they fire you'll be hit.
- 動手吧 開槍 - 他們看不見裡面 開槍會射中你
- I want you to thank me first. - Shut up and shoot.
- 我要你先謝謝我 弗蘭克 - 閉上嘴 開槍吧
All right, Frank.
好吧 弗蘭克
- All right, Frank. - Stand by to fire on my command.
- 好吧 弗蘭克 - 準備射擊
- Sleep well, my friend. - Just one thing, aim high.
- 睡個好覺 朋友 - 再說一句 打高處
- What? - Aim high!
- 什麼？- 打高處
- Now! - You bastard!
- 開槍 - 你這混蛋
Take my hand. If you don't, you'll die.
抓住我的手 否則你會摔死
- You want to save me, Frank? - To be honest, no. But it's my job.
- 你想救我 弗蘭克？- 跟你說實話我不想 可這是我的職責
Take it.
抓住
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
We've worked with Agent Horrigan for some time.
我們和霍利根先生共事很久了
He exemplifies courage and self- sacrifice. Frank!
對 弗蘭克是勇氣和自我棲牲的象徵
I guess I overreacted again, Harry.
這回我又反應過度了 哈瑞
Agent Horrigan, why are you retiring from the Secret Service?
霍利根先生 請問你為什麼決定從特工部退休？
Well, I hate desk work and I'm too old for running around.
因為我不喜歡坐辦公室 跟著汽車跑我又太老了
And thanks to all this press, I'm no good for undercover work.
感謝你們把我的照片登在報紙上 我再也不能做臥底工作了
How are you, Frank? The President sent his limo for you.
你好嗎 弗蘭克？弗蘭克 總統派他的車來接你
- That's the least he could do. - Good. I love public transportation.
- 噢 至少他能做到這點 - 好啊 可我喜歡坐公共汽車
Come on in.
請進
Make yourself at home.
隨便坐吧
- So, what do you think? - l like it.
- 覺得怎麼樣？- 我喜歡
Hello, Frank. By the time you hear this, it'll be over.
弗蘭克 聽到這段留言時 事情已經結束了
The President is most likely dead and so am I.
總統很可能已經死了 我也一樣
Frank, did you kill me? Who won our game? Not that it matters.
我想知道 是你殺死我的嗎？這場遊戲誰贏了？這並不重要
Among friends, like you and me, it's how you play the game.
朋友之間重要的不是輸贏 而是如何玩這場遊戲
The game's done.
現在遊戲結束了
It's time to get on with your life.
你可以重新面對生活
I worry that you have no life to get on with.
可我擔心你已經沒有生活可言
You're a good man.
你是個好人
Good men, like you and me, are destined to travel a lonely road.
像你我這樣的好人 註定要孤獨地走過漫漫長路
Goodbye and good luck.
永別了 祝你好運
I bet you that brown pigeon flies off before the white one.
我打賭 那只褐色的鴿子會比白鴿子先飛走
How do you know?
你怎麼知道？
I know things about pigeons, Lilly.
我很會看鴿子 莉莉